<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rachel's Blog</title><link>https://devineinspiration.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content on Rachel's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 23:58:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://devineinspiration.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SDN Performance and Security in Enterprise</title><link>https://devineinspiration.github.io/blog/posts/sdn-in-enterprise/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 23:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://devineinspiration.github.io/blog/posts/sdn-in-enterprise/</guid><description>Introduction With more and more large organisations relying on handling large amount of data traffic for their business operations, a high performant, resilient and flexible network solution is exactly what these organisations are looking for. A large amount of research has gone into the development and improvement of traditional networks with interest shifting recently into a different networking paradigm, Software Defined Networking.
Software Defined Networks (SDN), a term used to describe a form of network where the portions of the network responsible for the handling of transmitting data over a physical medium and the control of the flow of the data that is being sent over this medium is split away from a per device configuration.</description></item><item><title>Deployment and Securing of a LAMP Stack</title><link>https://devineinspiration.github.io/blog/posts/securing-lamp-stack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 01:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://devineinspiration.github.io/blog/posts/securing-lamp-stack/</guid><description>In this report/tutorial, deployment of a LAMP stack for use with WordPress is discussed, each of the technologies used explained and steps to secure the deployment on both a local virtual machine and on a public cloud. A comparison will be made between both of these deployments
Keywords— LAMP, Ubuntu, GCP, Public Cloud Web Development Platform, WordPress Server Security;
1. Introduction For many years now web developers have been looking for stable, secure and robust platforms for deploying their applications.</description></item><item><title>Securing an Apache Server with SELinux</title><link>https://devineinspiration.github.io/blog/posts/securing-apache-on-selinux/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://devineinspiration.github.io/blog/posts/securing-apache-on-selinux/</guid><description>In this report, the importance of the security of a webserver is discussed on modern deployments, as part of this, implementations demonstrating ways of securing a Apache webserver hosted on CentOS are shown with suitable explanation
*Keywords— Apache, SELinux, Web Hosting, Webserver, Server Security, CentOS; *
1. Introduction Apache is one of the most popular web servers currently being used across the internet, with 32.2% of all outward-facing web servers being hosted using Apache [1].</description></item><item><title>Analysis and Comparison of MAC Protocols for use in Wireless Sensor Networks</title><link>https://devineinspiration.github.io/blog/posts/mac-protocols-wsn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://devineinspiration.github.io/blog/posts/mac-protocols-wsn/</guid><description>In this paper, an investigation will be carried out to discover how different factors affect the energy consumption of a wireless sensor network. Three different MAC communication protocols (SMAC, TMAC and ZigBee) will be tested, with the effects of increased node density and sample rate on power consumption being monitored for analysis. The simulated network will be tested with two different radio hardware models (Texas Instruments CC1000 and CC2420) using the Castelia simulator within the OMNETPP Software Platform**</description></item></channel></rss>